### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/jorge-ayala-0a7a34112 (LinkedIn)

## Top Skills

English
Project Management
Engineering

## Languages

English (Professional Working) Spanish (Native or Bilingual)

## Certifications

Redes de comunicacion industriales Siemens

Programacion PLC LOGO! V8.2 Certificate of english language B2 SCADA WinCC

Certificado de capacitacion ocupacional INGLES SUPERIOR

## Honors-Awards

Excellence award

# Jorge Ayala

Ingeniero en Mecatrónica Guayaquil, Guayas, Ecuador

# Summary

As a mechatronics engineer I have been able to implement different projects related with mechanics, electronics, software and control design; within those projects I've been able to develop my skills in problem solving and teamwork communication. Furthermore, my job experience within different industries has allowed me to be responsible for different activities involving administrative and technical tasks.

I am passionate about optimizing processes. I consider that it has a great impact and influence in making people's lives easier. The opportunity to develop more efficient systems that generate better quality products or services can make a difference in current companies in the market.

My goal is to develop my professional career as a mechatronics engineer and be part of a company that allows me to apply my knowledge and skills so I can continue to grow both personally and professionally to achieve the best results.

# Experience

Agripac S.A.

Auxiliar de Mantenimiento

January 2022 - March 2022 (3 months)

- Evaluar, diagnosticar y diseñar procesos para proyectos y planificación para todo el organigrama empresarial.
- Gestionar procedimientos de mantenimiento preventivo y correctivo para equipos industriales.
- Llevar a cabo procesamiento de información referente a inventarios, servicios de mantenimiento, instalaciones y mejoras por medio de SAP y otros programas de gestión empresarial.
- Generar, registrar y presentar indicadores de gestión KPI, informes diarios sobre consumo de energía, planes de mantenimiento y gastos.

#### **ESPOL**

Ayudante de Docencia - Sistemas Embebidos May 2021 - October 2021 (6 months)

- Realizar programas en microcontroladores usando softwares de simulación para aplicaciones IoT.
- Elaborar reportes e informes para coordinación del curso.
- Asignar lecciones y calificar trabajos de desarrollo teórico y práctico.
- Preparar clases y contenido de la materia como talleres, vídeos, deberes, diapositivas y rubricas.

HVAC Ingeniería S.A. Asistente de Diseño Mecatronico February 2021 - April 2021 (3 months) Guayaquil, Guayas, Ecuador

- Controlar y monitorear equipos industriales en edificios por medio de softwares y de forma manual.
- Diseñar planos CAD de elementos mecanicos y de espacios industriales.
- Realizar informes técnicos, reportes, cotizaciones e inventarios referentes a equipos de instrumentación.
- Mantener comunicación con proveedores, clientes y personal de la empresa para el desarrollo de proyectos.

## Education

Escuela Superior Politécnica del Litoral Grado, Ingenieria Mecatronica · (October 2016 - February 2022)

#### **IPAC**

Bachiller, Ciencias exactas · (April 2011 - February 2016)